>>Now, we'll learn another technique to evaluate a model called
现在我们将学习另一个评估模型的技巧
the Receiver Operator Characteristic curve or ROC curve for short,
叫做受试者工作特性曲线 简称 ROC 曲线
and it works as follows.
它的工作原理如下
Consider this data which is now one dimensional,
有一组数据 现在是一维的
so all the red and blue points lie in one line,
所有红点和蓝点都在一条直线上
and we want to find the correct split.
我们想要找到正确的拆分方法
So, we can have a split like around here,
可以在这里拆分
or maybe here, or here.
这里或这里
All of them are good splits.
都是很好的拆分位置
So, we'll call this a good split.
我们称其为好的拆分
Now, we can look at this data which as you can see is perfectly separable over here.
现在看看这组数据 看出可以在这里完美地拆分
So, we'll call that a perfect split.
我们称其为完美拆分
And finally, we have this data over here which is pretty much random,
最后是这个非常随机的数据
and there's not much to split here.
没有可拆分的位置
It seems that anywhere we put the boundary,
似乎在任何地方放置界线
we'll have about half blue,
每侧都有一半的蓝点
half red points on each side.
和一半的红点
So, we'll call that a bad split or a random split.
我们称其为坏的拆分或随机拆分
And now what we want is to come up with a metric or
现在要做的是得出一个指标或数字
some number that is high for the perfect split,
对于完美拆分来说很高
medium for the good split,
对于好的拆分来说中等大小
and low for the random split.
对于随机拆分来说很低
In fact, something that gives the perfect split a score of one,
实际上 让完美拆分的得分为 1
the good split something around 0.8,
好的拆分在 0.8 左右
and the random split something around 0.5.
随机拆分在 0.5 左右
That's where the ROC curve will help us.
这时候 ROC 曲线就能派上用场了
So, let's see how to construct these numbers.
我们看看如何构建这些数字
Let's take our good data and let's cut it over here.
我们看看好的数据 在这里拆分
Now, we'll calculate two ratios.
现在计算两个比例
The first one is a true positive rate, which means,
第一个是真阳性比例
out of all the positively labeled points,
即在所有阳性标记的点中
how many did we classify correctly?
有多少点分类正确？
That means, the number of true positives,
也就是真阳性的点数量
divided by the total number of positively labeled points.
除以阳性标记的点总数
So, let's see how much this is.
看看结果是多少
There are seven positively labeled numbers,
有 7 个阳性标记的数字
and six of them have been correctly labeled positive.
其中 6 个正确地标记为阳性
So, this ratio is six out of seven, or 0.857.
比例是 6/7 等于 0.857
Now, let's look at the false positive rate which means out of all the negative points,
现在看看假阳性比例 即在所有阴性点中
how many of them did the model incorrectly think they were positives?
模型错误地认为有多少点是阳性的
So out of the seven negatively labeled points,
在 7 个阴性标记的点中
the model thought two of them were positive.
模型认为有 2 个是阳性的
So the false positive rate is two out of seven, or 0.286.
因此假阳性比例是 2/7 等于 0.286
And we'll just remember these two numbers.
我们只需记住这两个数字
Now, what we'll do,
我们要做的是
is we'll move this boundary around and calculate the same pair of numbers.
四处移动这个界线 并计算相同的数字对
So, let's play it over here.
放在这里
What is the true positive rate over here?
真阳性比例是多少？
Well, the model thinks everything is positive.
模型认为所有点都是阳性的
So in particular, all the positives are true positives.
因此所有阳性点都是真的阳性
So, the true positive rate is seven divided by seven, which is one.
真阳性比例是 7/7 等于 1
And for the false positive rate.
对于假阳性比例
Well, since the model thinks everything is positive,
因为模型认为所有点都是阳性
then all the negatives are false positive.
因此所有阴性都是假阳性
So, the false positive rate is again seven divided by seven, which is one.
因此假阳性比例是 7/7 等于 1
So again, we'll remember these two values one and one.
记住这两个值 1 和 1
And now let's go to the other extreme.
再看看另一个极端情况
Let's put the bar over here and now let's see what is the true positive rate.
将界线放在这里 现在看看真阳性比例
Well, the model thinks nothing is positive.
模型认为所有点都不是阳性
So in particular, there are no true positives and the ratio is zero divided by seven,
因此没有真阳性 比例是 0/7 等于 0
which is zero. And for the false positive rate?
那么假阳性比例呢？
Well, again, the model thinks nothing is positive,
模型认为没有点是阳性
so there are no false positives.
因此没有假阳性
And the ratio is zero over seven, which again is zero.
比例是 0/7 等于 0
And we'll remember these two numbers.
记住这两个数字
We can see that no matter how the data looks,
可以看出无论数据是怎样的
the two extremes will always be one,
两个极端始终为 (1,1)
one and zero, zero.
和 (0,0)
And now, we can do this for every possible split and record those numbers.
现在可以计算所有可能的拆分情况 并记下这些数字
So here we have a few of them that we've calculated.
我们计算出了几个值
And now, the magic happens.
现在比较神奇的是
We just pluck these numbers in the plane, and we get a curve.
我们将这些数字代入平面里 得出了一条曲线
And now, we calculate the area under the curve and here we get around 0.8.
我们计算曲线下方的面积 大约是 0.8
This is actually not accurate, but it's around there.
不太准确 但是大概这么多
You can calculate it on your own and see how much you get.
你可以自己计算下 看看结果是多少
So now, let's do the same thing for the perfect split.
我们现在对完美拆分执行相同的流程
Here are all the ratios.
这是所有的比例结果
Notice that the boundary is on the red side,
注意如果界线在红色那一侧
and the true positive ratio is
真阳性比例是 1
one since every positive number has been predicted positive.
因为每个阳性点都被预测为阳性
Similarly, if the boundaries on the blue side then every negative number
类似地 如果界线在蓝色一侧
has been predicted negative and so the false positive ratio is zero.
那么所有阴性点都被预测为阴性 因此假阳性比例是 0
In particular, at the perfect split point,
尤其是 在完美拆分点
we have a zero comma one.
结果是 (0,1)
Thus, when we pluck these numbers,
代入这些数字后
the curve looks like a square,
曲线看起来像个正方形
and the square has area one, which means,
正方形的面积是 1
the area under the ROC curve for the perfect split is one.
也就是完美拆分的 ROC 曲线下方的面积是 1
And finally, we do this for the random split.
最后看看随机拆分
In here, you can try it on your own.
你可以自己试试
But basically, since every split leaves on each side around half blue, half red points,
因为每种拆分都让每侧一半的蓝点和一半的红点
many pair of numbers will be close to each other,
很多数字对都将相互接近
and the curve will be very close to being
曲线将非常接近
just a diagonal between zero, zero and one, one.
一个(0,0) 和 (1,1) 之间的三角形
So if the model is random,
如果模型是随机的
then the area under the ROC curve is around 0.5.
那么 ROC 曲线下方的面积约为 0.5
So to summarize, we have three possible scenarios:
总结下 有三个可能的情形
some random data which is hard to split,
一些难以拆分的随机数据
some pretty good data which we can split well making some errors,
一些很好拆分偶尔出现错误的良好数据
and some perfectly divided data which we can split with no errors.
以及拆分后没有错误的完美拆分数据
And each one is associated with a curve,
每个都有一个曲线
and the areas under the curve are close to 0.5 for the random model.
随机模型的曲线下面积接近 0.5
Some are close to one for the good model,
一些接近 1
so around 0.8 and one for the perfect model.
对好的模型来说大约为 0.8 完美模型是 1
So in summary, the closer your area under the ROC curve is to one,
总结下 ROC 曲线下的面积越接近 1
the better your model is.
模型就越好
Now here is a question,
现在提个问题
can the area under the curve be less than 0.5?
曲线下的面积可以小于 0.5 吗？
In fact, yes, it can be all the way to zero.
实际上可以 可以一直为 0
How would a model look if the area under the curve is zero?
如果曲线下面积为 0 模型该是怎样的？
Well, it will look more backwards.
看起来就更倒退
It'll have more blue points in the red area,
红色区域有更多的蓝点
and the red points in the blue area.
蓝色区域有更多的红点
So maybe flipping the data may help.
或许翻转数据会有帮助